It is 6 pm. I now call the February 2nd,
2026 meeting of the city of Cheyenne
Planning Commission to order. Staff,
please call the role.
Daryl Hibbons
>> here.
Lonnie Olsson here.
>> Megan Connor.
>> Amy Hernandez
>> present.
>> Bob Matia
>> here.
>> Boyd Wiggle
>> present. Via Zoom.
>> Tony Lair
>> here.
>> Mr. Chair, we do have a quorum.
>> First item on the agenda. May I have a
motion for approval of the minutes of
January 5th, 2026?
>> So moved.
>> Uh, a second.
>> Any discussion or comments about those
draft minutes?
Hearing none. All in favor of approval,
please signify by saying I. I. I. I.
>> The same sign.
Minutes are approved.
Staff, please read item A into the
record.
Item A, PUDC-25-271,
Village Cooperative Expedited Plat.
Will the applicant or agent please come
in podium to explain the request? Yes,
chairman. Uh, planning commission
members Brad Evans, AVI, uh, agents for
the owners, section 20 LLC and the Cole
family and the applicant, which is
Village Cooperative. Um, and I'll
probably speak to both one and two a
little bit and just kind of go through
it all. But, um, before you is a
expedited plat, preliminary plat at this
stage uh, for a single lot and
additional Melton Road um, rightway. Um
the plat is being considered to uh
create a lot for the village cooperative
uh senior housing co-op um which is a
little bit of a unique uh s setup
different than we've had in Cheyenne in
the past and we do have a representative
from village cooperative here to speak
um to give a little background on that
as well. Um we've uh also uh started the
site plan process uh with the city um to
make sure that we're covering all our
bases at the same time in case we needed
to change the lot size or those kinds of
things as well. So if there's questions
about the that we can answer them today
as well. Um the um one access will come
off of Powder House and one access will
come off of uh the new Milton Road that
will be built with the project and be um
the next item which is to change the
zoning. Uh the zoning is required to be
NR3 for this project. So we are going
through that at the same time. Um and
I'll have the applicant come up and then
we can stand for any questions that the
planning commission has.
Uh good evening. Uh my name is Andrew
Schaefer and I'm with uh Real Estate
Equities Development Company. Uh we are
based out of Minnesota. uh and we uh
about 20 years ago started specializing
in the development of senior housing
cooperatives which are somewhat of a
little bit of a unique uh product type
that um I don't believe there are any
here in Cheyenne but um we've uh been
developing for about 20 years and a
cooperative senior housing cooperative
is is an ownership housing option for u
people over 62 and it gives them the
option to purchase a share in the
cooperative corporation. Um they
collectively will own the entire
building, the land, uh all the
amenities. Uh the community is uh
designed or proposed to be 54 homes and
uh three stories with an underground
parking garage. um some exterior garden
plots, uh interior community spaces, uh
club room areas, uh guest suites,
exercise room, uh hobby rooms, and um we
have successfully developed
um I think over 40 existing communities
that are up and operating and then we've
got um another six or seven that are
either under construction or in planning
stages. So, we've successfully developed
uh 10 of these communities in the Denver
area. I'll call it the Front Range. Um,
and we've got two others currently under
construction. And we also have uh other
communities in about nine or 10 other
states. So, we're super excited to be
here um to be proposing this uh
community here in Cheyenne. And uh with
that, I'd welcome any questions you may
have.
Commissioners, any questions for the
applicant?
Mr. Chair, Boyd Wigum, through you. Um,
and and maybe this is better directed to
the to the agent for the applicant than
to the applicant. Um, but I I note that
uh one of the exceptions that is being
requested is to um our maximum block
size.
Um, similar to other
proposals that have have occurred in
this general vicinity,
can we talk about what we can do to
ensure that when when this plat comes
and goes and it's developed and comes
back up later,
what can we do to ensure that
we're protecting the, you know, right
now obviously not likely to have a lot
of pedestrian activity just because of
the stage of development this area is
in. But but to protect the ability of
pedestrians to get from here to there
in the city as the city becomes more
urban.
What what are are there any plans to
build pedestrian facilities to ensure
that this thing somebody can get get
through this if they're on foot
rather than rather than having to walk
around the entire circumference of this
oversized block?
Chairman through you to uh the planning
commission members. Um so again on on
this site the um we will be building the
road on the north side which will be uh
having pedestrian access on the north
and then obviously on the west. Um
there's really no other additional
places for pedestrians in this area.
Life Care Center owns all the land to
the south and this uh Melton is on the
master land use plan. though we have um
got it extended to the the distance that
it is required through that. Um I don't
believe that
the
interconnectivity from a pedestrian
standpoint would be
necessary on the south end of this. Um I
guess that would be the only other
location there. Um, as Melton continues
about
about half this block size to the east,
I believe, then there's a a road coming
up from the south that connects Story
all the way down to um basically the the
road in front of the mall. So, um I I
guess in this situation, I don't see the
need for pedestrian access on the south
end to get over there as there will be
additional roads from the east end um
from that road that comes from I think
that's Frontier Mall Drive that's just
to the south of this. But, um
could answer any other questions of the
commission.
>> What kind of what size building is it
going to be? one solid one big building
that's going to fill the block or I mean
it's not going to be a two or three like
apartment size
>> chairman through you yeah it's a typ
it's it's a three-story building one one
building so there's not multiple
buildings um there is a fire lane that
goes around the south side of it there's
an exit there'll be an exit on Melton
and an exit on Powderhouse so there'll
be an access on Powder House right
across from the road south of Melton
which for some reason I is that Hoy
>> Yep.
>> Hoy road and then um and then an access
off of the new Melton that will be built
with Melton. So there'll be a new road
on the north side of this which I
believe Melton does go at least halfway
across the coal property and the and the
master transportation plan and might go
all the way across. It's going to run
into the apartments on the east end
probably Routt. Yeah, it would go at
least all the way to Routt.
>> Do you know where Milton is going to
extend to through going going to the
east?
>> So, I believe it only goes to Router,
which is about the Lowe's.
>> No, not the Lowe's. It'd be the next uh
Michaels. So, Michaelels would be the
the building where Melton ends.
>> Okay. Thank you.
Any
other questions for the applicant? Uh,
Commissioner Wigum, did you get good
answer about the block size exception?
>> Mr. Chair, I don't think I'm satisfied,
but I think that's clarification. We'll
need to talk about that a little later,
I think, after we hear from staff.
>> Any other questions for the applicant?
Mr. Chair, I hear you. for Andrew. Can I
grab you before you have a seat there?
Um
I'd like to see if you can tell us a
little bit more about
um how what you're building is so much
more different and a step above uh what
we're currently seeing in our area.
Yeah, it's um a cooperative community is
just a little bit different form of
ownership. So, you commonly will see uh
a lot of uh senior rentals um but not a
whole lot of just dedicated senior
ownership options. Uh so, the
cooperative kind of combines uh all of
the benefits of owning um
people generally would like to move into
communities that they own, not not rent
and don't have control over the
community. So, that's a huge benefit to
the cooperative. Um, the other benefits
are there's benefits that are more
similar to renting where there's on-site
staff to take care of things. So, people
can get rid of the home ownership
maintenance side of things. Uh, so there
is a part-time manager who will manage
the community. There is a part-time
maintenance person who will take care of
all of the regular maintenance, even
changing batteries and smoke detectors,
changing filters and the furnaces. Uh,
all of those are taken care of by the
community, so the people that live there
don't have to maintain anything. Uh
obviously all the exterior services are
all contracted for. So whether it's um
lawn care, snow removal, any of that
type of stuff is all taken care of. Um
the biggest thing I would say that's
kind of unique about these cooperative
communities is we pre-ell uh at least 50
to 60% of the homes before we will break
ground on the project.
uh we've already got uh about 50 or a
little bit more than 50% of the homes uh
spoken for and so it's been very uh very
good start to the project as far as just
the interest level in it. Um and they
get to know each other uh through the
process of u pre-elling it through the
the construction. So, we have monthly
meetings with all of the people who are
going to be eventually moving into the
community so they can kind of
participate in the in the process of the
development and the construction. Uh, we
also allow them to to make individual uh
finish selections so they can kind of
customize their their homes. So, when
they move into them, it's not like
you're moving into a community where
they're all the same. Uh, you can pick
your cabinets, your countertops, your
flooring, your appliances, all of those
types of things. And then really what's
kind of unique about them is the
cooperative ownership really kind of
ties the community together. There's uh
a lot of social interaction within the
community. Every community is a little
different. It's not like um there's
someone spearheading that there has to
be these types of social interactions.
But generally speaking, uh each
community is a little unique, but
there's typically uh regular happy
hours. There's card there's card groups.
There's gettogethers on holidays.
There's typically a Super Bowl party in
the community, you name it. They have a
lot of things going on just organically.
Um, so a lot of people will tell me once
they've moved in, I wanted to get out of
my house and get get out of the
maintenance of the home uh or out of
steps if they didn't want to be in a
home with steps anymore down to or up
two different floors or down to the the
laundry. Um, and then once they get
there, they really enjoy kind of the
social side of it.
Chair,
>> I've got a kind of a followup to that if
somebody else wants to speak.
>> Go ahead, Commissioner Wigum.
>> Kind of following up on on the
cooperative
structure. Uh, one, would it be fair to
I'm curious about the government
governance because
uh there's going to be one of the things
we run into in this community is is
sometimes having difficulty getting
uh drainage detention pond type stuff
maintained. Is this cooperative
community kind of like an HOA on
steroids? What's the govern what does
the governance structure look like? And
as we're looking specifically at this
plat,
what are we looking like uh with with a
cooperative like this? What are we
looking at that would be different terms
interfacing with
maintenance of the things that would
normally be maintained by the individual
owners?
>> Yes. Um so the coop it's the the
ownership entity is it'll be the village
cooperative of Cheyenne. Uh it's a it's
a cooperative corporation that has
already been formed. Um each uh
each home uh to to purchase a home, you
don't really purchase the home. It's not
like you're buying a condominium where
you get a deed to uh a space in a
building if it's a multi-story building
or a deed to a little chunk of land.
They actually purchase a share in that
cooperative corporation and then that uh
gives them the right to occupy a
particular home in the building. So they
actually will sign uh subscription
paperwork to become a member in the
cooperative and then they will also sign
an occupancy agreement once they take
occupancy of the home. There will be uh
54 shareholders
um and there will be a five member board
of directors that will govern the
cooperative corporation. I would say
it's extremely similar and organized
like an HOA is, but it is in our
experience they're much more active in
the governance of the community. Um they
typically will have monthly board
meetings, uh make decisions just about
the operation of the community, approve
their budgets, uh any improvements they
want to make. And uh our first village
cooperative we developed in 2004, so
just over 20 years ago. It's in Fergus
Falls, Minnesota, which is a small town.
Someone's probably not here ever heard
of it, but I will tell you they are
impeccably cared for. Uh the people
really take pride of ownership in the
communities and uh I can assure you
won't have any maintenance issues that
uh they don't take care of. So whether
it be storm detention issues or anything
in the community and I do know uh we did
take um I believe uh the mayor and the
director of planning down to tour one of
our communities in Fort Collins and they
were extremely impressed just with what
they saw there and they talked to the
the members we call them that live there
members of the cooperative. So
hopefully that addresses and can answer
any further questions about that
>> Mr. share through you. So, are they
individual
residents or is it like a apartment
complex type?
>> Uh, so the the building structure would
be more similar to what you would say an
apartment looks like. It's a three-story
structure uh built over a podium style,
which is a underground garage. So, you
won't see the garage on um the street
side of the building. there will be an
entrance to drive down into it on the
east side of the building just because
of the way the grades um transition
there from the high side being west to
the low side being east. Um and then
within the building uh there's an
elevator um and corridors and access to
the home similar to an apartment.
>> How many units?
>> Uh 54 units. Yep. We like to keep our
communities in that kind of 50 to 80
unit range. uh they operate well. Um
they're not too big where people don't
know who's living there. They it's it's
a manageable size where they know their
neighbors and they seem to function the
best in that size.
>> Mr. Chairman, through you do you do you
maintain some kind of relationship with
the cooperative after it's all filled
and so sold off and things?
>> Yeah, so we uh we do maintain an ongoing
relationship. Uh there's commonly just
questions like a board of directors will
call me personally and just be like,
"Hey, we're running into this issue.
Have you seen this on any of your other
communities?" Uh we do not provide the
property management services. Um we do
work with a company that uh you know we
hire to do that and and they will step
in when the community is ready to occupy
and start managing it. um and they're
more of a full-ervice property
management company where we're a more of
a developer, but we do keep an ongoing
relationship with them and support them.
We also um you know once the community
is sold out, typically we'll break
ground on the project and have at least
60% of it spoken for and then the rest
of the homes will sell while it's under
construction. In most of our
communities, the day the doors open for
occupancy, they're sold out. And then we
uh create a weight list and then we help
the community continue to market uh on
our website um and kind of add people to
their weight list. Uh as um after
occupancy typically uh there's a pretty
healthy weight list that gets developed.
On average I would say our communities
have anywhere from 10 to 40 people on
their weight list. Uh so when a home
becomes available um they simply have to
notify the manager in the building that
they would they'd like to move out or
they need to move out and then the
manager in the building will utilize the
wait list for the next buyer.
That next buyer will come in and
purchase the the share uh of the that
represents that home and then the person
that's moving out gets their share back.
Uh, and there's also the bylaws have a
controlled appreciation. So, the shares
will increase by 3% every year. Uh, so
they'll get their original share
purchase plus the appreciation back when
they move out.
>> Mr. Chairman, through you. Um,
when you when a person wants to sell,
does he is he allowed to advertise his
share for sale on on the open market or
do you have to go through something?
Well, uh, if a member wants to sell
their share, they are allowed to sell it
independently if they want. Uh, but
since the community has that weight
list, um, most people utilize it cuz
it's it's easy. You know, there's a a
weight list of people that want to get
into the community and that's the
quickest and easiest way for them to
resell. So, that's usually the way that
people resell. If they don't want to do
that and they want to sell it to maybe
they have a friend or a or someone like
that or you know family acquaintance or
a sister or brother that they want to
sell it to, they can do that directly.
Or if they want to um list it or sell it
uh independently, they could. It's just
the weight list is most utilized.
Mr. Chair,
um call it an occupational hazard. Um,
we're talking about these wonderful
weight lists and selling out.
We approve this, it moves forward. What
is the minimum o occupancy rate
necessary for one of these things to be
viable and to be continuing forward, not
have to be vacated because the income
doesn't
just doesn't pay for it.
>> Yeah. Um, good good question. you know,
it's it's ownership housing, so it's
unlike an apartment where there's
vacancy factors. Uh, so all of the homes
will be sold and there will be a buyer
or an owner of every share and every
home in that cooperative um
forever, I guess, unless they default
and and walk away from the cooperative,
which honestly I don't, to my knowledge,
that has never happened. Uh, I mean,
typically, um, there's a wait list of
people that are ready to move in, and
people aren't going to, since they're
purchasing a share in the cooperative,
they're not going to walk away from that
investment. Um, and
um, so it's 100% occupied. I mean, it's
100%
occupied as far as there are
shareholders. Now, if someone needs to
move out and the the home is vacant for
a couple months, while they're reselling
it, that's about the only time there
would be a vacancy. And it's not
necessarily a vacancy. It's just
someone's not living in the home they
own.
>> Is it as a follow-up question, is it
possible for someone who is under the
age of 62 to own a share?
>> Um, so is it possible for someone under
62? No. Everyone needs to be 62 or over
who occupies. There are ways where we've
had um
like the children sponsor the the share
ownership, but the occupant needs to be
62 or over. So, there are some methods
to do that, but everyone that lives
there is typically 62 or over.
Again, occupational hazard. So if the 62
year old or older person passes away and
leaves their share to,
you know, in Wyoming it would be a
child.
How does that work for you?
>> Yeah. So if if someone unfortunately
passes away while they're living in the
cooperative and a member of the
cooperative, um it would be whatever
their estate wants to have happen. um
they can put the share like any other
asset into, you know, they could put it
into a trust, they can do a living uh
living will, they can do all this
different types of things. So, you know,
unless there's a child that's 62 that
wants to move into it or there's some
other person that it goes through uh
through their will, um most of the time
the family would just ask the
cooperative to please resell the the
share to someone on the wait list and
then their estate would receive the
proceeds from the resell the share.
And one last question, totally different
topic and I maybe you answered this
already. What percentage of the
footprint of your lot is going to be
occupied by the building?
Do you know that
the footprint of the building is
approximately
I think 30,000 square feet. That's
approximate. And it's on a 3.5 acre
site. So less than 25%.
For the building itself.
>> Yep. And so that get back to what my
comment question was earlier
about
providing for a way from a pedestrian to
get from east to west through the middle
of the property or north to south
through the middle of the property if
somebody finds themselves a foot and
having to get
having to go that way.
Well, there's the building is in about
the center of the property and there are
sidewalks around the property as well as
a surface parking lot. So, I mean, as
far as getting around the the lot, uh
there are sidewalks and paths to do that
to get from that lot to the other areas.
I'd have to rely upon
>> Isimeter going to be fenced or something
that would prevent pedestrian access
other than
uh coming in off offer house. Yeah,
there there's no intent to fence any any
part of the property. Okay.
And
>> thank you, Mr. Chair. I think I'm done.
>> Other questions from the commissioners?
Okay. Hearing none, we can hear the
staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, commissioners, Morgan Dennis,
Planning and Development. This plat is
for land generally north of Prairie
Avenue, east of Powder House Road and
west of Rotair.
Rio property to be known as lot one
block one of Village Cooperative.
The proposed plat will be creating a lot
that will be used for highdensity senior
residential development. This land is
currently being annexed from the county
to the city. A zone change is running
concurrent with this plat.
The future land use map designates this
area as urban residential. Surrounding
properties include residential and
commercial uses. The proposed lot is
buildable and is considered MD1 per the
UDC. There is an exception to this law.
This plat There is an exception to this
plat. The plat takes place on an
oversized block. Um an extension of
Melton Street is dedicated on the plat.
The extension will connect to other
streets as the area continues to
develop. I stand for questions.
>> Questions for the staff.
>> Mr. Chair, through you through you. This
is this is Boyd Wigum. Um,
Morgan,
were there any internal discussions with
staff about about the oversized uh block
issue that we've kind of talked about?
Um, and and that exception.
Um, is is was there anything that staff
was hoping to to have provided that
didn't get that didn't get provided in
the final application here?
related to that.
>> Mr. Chair, this is Seth Lloyd with
Planning and Development. I'll take that
question if that's all right.
>> Um,
so the village cooperative property by
itself is not an oversized block. If
someone put streets all around the
village cooperative property, it would
easily meet block size standards. Um, if
you put four if you put two village
cooperative plats together, it would
meet block size standards. If you put
four, it wouldn't. Um, so the challenge
here is that this project is taking
place on a much much much larger block.
Um, and we also have the challenge of
Powderhouse Road being a minor arterial,
which means our access uh road spacing
is 660 ft. Um, so we
our engineering department wouldn't
allow a second street on the south side
of this property because of powderhouse
being a minor arterial. um 660 feet
would be all the way down not just to
Hoy but another I think it's Mchugh or
whatever the next street south is and
even that's not exactly 660 ft but we
wouldn't want offset intersection so if
we had another street come out through
this area going east west it would
probably be down there is where we'd
want it so it's not really logical to do
anything more than what they are doing
with this plat they are dedicating
Melton Street going um to the edge of
their boundary which is really all we
can expect of the applicant for this
particular property in this particular
situation. But at the end of the day,
the fact of the matter is the the block
is still too big. And even if this if
this if we had four equivalent projects
all next to each other on one large
block, it still would not meet block
standards. So it it doesn't meet the
letter of the law. Um, but as far as
this particular situation goes, it's
about as good as we can really
reasonably expect.
>> Would it, as a followup, would it be
possible to get sidewalks at the
perimeter even if we don't have streets
or do we even have anything like that in
our UDC or is that something we need to
deal with?
>> Miss Mr. Chair.
>> Yeah, Mr. Chair, through you. Um the
there are exceptions to block sizes in
the UDC that allow for pedestrian
connections in um certain zone
districts. Um
but it's not universal to the UDC and
the application of that standard. Um I
still don't think would meet block size
in this particular scenario. Um it is
something that we have brought up to the
governing body at the annual review work
session we had with them earlier this
month um as a possible discussion point
to kind of um rightsize our block
standard regulations um prioritize
pedestrian connections um but at this
time we don't really have um a good
process there and um
as far as it goes as I said I I think
that what they've provided is about as
good as we would reasonably expect for
this project. They are providing a full
street on the north side of their
property which um is much more than a
pedestrian connection. It's vehicle
connection as well.
>> Okay. Thank you. Thank you, Mr. Chair.
>> Other questions for staff?
>> I I guess I have one that isn't directly
related. Uh but so the lifecare property
the borders to the south I know quite a
bit of or that part of it is
undeveloped. Do do we know does life
care plan to expand and utilize that?
>> We do not know what the plans are for
that property that's the vac bas
essentially vacant land between here and
life between this subject property and
the lifeare property. Um, we we'd have
to address that development when it came
forward.
Any other questions for staff?
Okay, we will now open it up for public
comments. Is there anyone who would like
to speak either in favor or against the
proposal?
And if you could please state your name
and address. If there's anyone here in
person, come to the podium. If there's
someone online.
No one online, Connor, that we're
looking for.
Just as a reminder for those online, if
you do have comments, please use the
raise hand feature.
Okay. Hearing no public comment. Uh
we're closing public comment is closing
once, closing twice, closing three
times. It's closed.
So we'll entertain a motion from the
commission.
Mr. Chair, I move to approve the village
cooperative preliminary plat advancing
the final plat to the governing body
with the following exception. Uh number
one, an exception to block size.
>> Second,
>> Mr. Chair,
I I really would prefer to have
something that would be a proposal to to
further mitigate the the need for a
block size exception.
Uh perhaps, you know,
future dedication along that southern
boundary when when the property to the
south develops or something. I I I wish
we had something. I've We've talked
about it before that
I really think that our block size
regulations exist to ensure that
pedestrians can get from point A to
point B without taking excessively
circuitous routes just cuz the
excessively circuitous routes are work
well for cars. Uh when you're a foot, it
doesn't always work the same.
With that, I'll probably vote to support
support this, but I think this is an
issue that is a recurring issue and and
we need to find a solution for it before
we leave our pedestrians high and drive.
I would just add that it uh seems to be
a recurring issue in this section anyway
because we've had it in a discussion
several times uh with plats in this
particular section. So I maybe it's just
unique because it's a big open area
that's being developed for peace meal
and we're not quite sure. It's not like
there's some big master plan that's
putting all the pieces together from the
beginning.
Any other uh discussion on the motion?
Hearing none. Staff, can you call the
RO?
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Yes.
Amy Hernandez.
>> Hi.
>> Wid Wiggum.
>> Lonnie Olsson.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay. Staff, could you please read item
B into the record?
>> Item B, PUDC-25-272,
village cooperative zone change.
It's the same same applicant, same
agent. I
>> chairman, planning commission members,
Brad Emmens, AVI. Just if you have any
questions, we'd be happy to answer them.
>> Chair, I guess I have one probably more
for the applicant, but uh it's just is
this your first project within the state
of Wyoming? I know you said you had
multiple going on. I was just curious if
this is your first branch into our
state. Uh yes, this would be our first
community in in Wyoming.
Other questions on So this is the item
involving the zone change from
agricultural to NR3.
Any other questions to the applicant or
agent about that?
>> Maybe this is a Mr. Chair through you.
This might be for the staff. Is there
other parts of this adjacent land that's
still in the county that we could bring
in? And
>> Mr. Chair, I can actually take that
question. Uh, Conor Way Planning and
Development Department. Um, so basically
this plat and the area around it is
currently part of county pocket
annexation number nine. Uh, that is
planned to be on third reading next
Monday. So third and final. Um, and
right now it has a recommendation of
approval coming from committee today. So
we're expecting it's going to be annexed
as of next Monday and we'll annex the
entirety of section 20 in this area.
>> Any other questions for the applicant?
Hearing none. Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, commissioners Morgan Dennis,
Planning and Development. Um, like we've
said, this is the concurrent zone change
with the plat. Um, as previously stated,
uh, this future land use map designates
this area as urban residential. Um, this
designation does promote residential
developments of several types.
Multi-unit residential developments are
appropriate within this designation.
uh surrounding zoning is lowdensity
residential, agriculture and mixeduse
business. The LR zone area is the Indian
Hills neighborhood development um which
consists of single family dwellings. The
AG zone personals are just holding zones
until developmental action can be taken
on them. And the MUB zone is just a
parking lot and vacant
which is connected to the life center
property. I stand for questions.
>> Questions for staff on this item.
>> Hearing none, I'll open it up for public
comment. Is there anyone from the public
who would like to address this item
either for or against?
Public comment going once, going twice,
public comment going three times. Public
comment is closed. Uh I forgot to ask on
the last item, but applicant, do you
have anything else you'd like to add
based on Okay.
>> I will now entertain a motion from the
commission.
Chair, I move to approve the resoning
lot one block one village cooperative to
NR3 highdensity residential as shown in
the attached zone change map noting that
the project meets review criteria for
approval.
>> Second.
>> Any discussion on the item?
>> Hearing none. Staff, could you call the
role?
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> Yes.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Id
Wigum.
>> I.
>> Lonnie Olsen.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Staff, please call or read item C into
the record.
Item C, PUDC-
25-278,
county pocket annexation number 10,
assigned zoning.
>> So, this item is sponsored by staff,
correct? So, we'll just have that
report.
>> Mr. chair and uh members of the
commission Connor White planning and
development permit.
So again, this is another assigned
zoning. These go along with the
annexation. Um
but this is strictly the zoning aspect.
Um as the annexation does not come
before you is just the zoning portion.
So this is the final county pocket
annexation. So you shouldn't see any
more of these. Um, county pocket ones
coming forward.
This area is located east of I25, south
of the intersection of Westland Road and
Missile Drive, north of West and East
Allison Road, and then east of and
adjacent to North College Drive. So,
this is kind of all over the place. Um,
we kind of looked at this as it's our
cleanup uh county pocketation.
is the remaining pockets as we got away
from the larger sections um in the city.
So, I'm going to go through each of
these areas, each of the pockets. Um you
probably noticed in the staff report
there was quite a bit of discussion on
one of the pockets be pocket number six.
So, I'm just going to go through these
and kind of um explain what staff is
recommending the assigned zones be.
Uh so with parcel one, which is that
northern small parcel, it is currently
zoned all in the county. Um it basically
contains a city-owned property that's
basically used as an alley and two
residential properties. Um staff is
recommending that that be assigned the
LI zone. Um even though it has
residential properties in it, this whole
area is LI. um those residential
properties are already non-conforming in
the county, so they'll just continue as
non-conforming coming into the city.
Pocket two and three are not really
parcels. Uh they're more or less uh
railroad rights of way. Um
the top one would be parcel 2 that is
also zoned LI. So we would just
recommend that that be continued as LI.
and the southern one is CB. We just
recommend that continue as CB.
Going on to parcel or pocket 4. Um right
now this is zoned LU in the county. So
land use. Uh it does have a residence
and currently is a farm with a farm
stand. Um staff is recommending that
this be zoned to AG agriculture. Um, the
AG zone basically allows those uses to
continue as permitted uses. So, they
won't be considered non-conforming.
They're permitted uses, their uses by
right, allowed to continue, allowed to
expand um should that property owner
wish to uh and does not change the
current use of the property. So again,
we'd recommend that northern parcel B A.
The southern pocket, uh, that pocket is
all residential.
Um, it's currently zoned urban
residential, low density in the county.
Um, looking at the surrounding zones
with that parcel,
the closest kind of residential zone
that is city is actually MR, so medium
density residential. Looking further at
the lots, they are more developed uh
similar to our medium density
residential zone. So staff would
recommend that pocket uh become medium
density residential upon annexation
parcel or pocket number six. Um this was
a long one to review and have a bit of
discussion in the staff report. Uh staff
looked at multiple zone districts for
this one. Uh we looked at the AG zone,
the NR3, CB, MUR, MUB, MUE, and even the
LI.
Um
with this parcel right now, it's mostly
an industrial use on it. Uh they've got
a outdoor storage yard, some warehouses.
It's a communication company that
currently owns it. It is surrounded by
the NR3. Um and that NR3 zone is being
developed with multif family.
Um
the ownership for the NR3 that is along
Fox Farm is not the same ownership as um
the parcels that are to the north being
developed. So those parcels along Fox
Farm could be zoned to a different uh
zoning than NR3. So we aren't sure
exactly if NR3 will develop there with
residential or not uh because it's not
the same ownership. So, we looked at the
NR3 as being an option because it is
surrounded.
Um,
and then we did look at possibly the MUB
or even MUE for this parcel.
Uh, MUB would give that mixture of both
commercial and residential allowance.
Um, but it does have stricter design
standards. It does have um kind of block
size requirements and things like that.
Looking at the MUE, MUE is more
kind of limited industrial focused, more
campuslike when it comes to kind of
industrial style development. So, it
looks at more industrial style campuses
where the MUE basically the only
residential it allows is apartments.
Um, and it doesn't allow any of the
other residential options.
And then the LI zone, uh, it's currently
zoned LI in the county. uh that's the
current use of the property.
Um
and as we kind of looked at the various
options, staff felt that just giving
them the LI zone would probably be um
the better option as that is the current
use. That doesn't limit them on
expanding their current use. um and
allows them to continue developing it if
they wish. And looking towards the
future, if somebody did buy that square
and they did want to reszone it to a
residential zone, they have that option.
Um but at least giving it LI, it's the
closest match to what their current use
is, what the current county zone is. Um
and then doesn't really limit their
options with what they're currently
doing.
The last parcel, um, we actually broke
this up into two separate
recommendations. Uh, basically the way
that I looked at it is you've got 7A and
7B.
7A being that northern LI portion and or
7 Yeah. And then 7B being the LU land
use portion on the south half or south
uh, third.
staff would recommend the LI zoning for
that northern uh portion that is
currently zoned LI in the county. The
current use on there is industrial.
They're warehousing and some trucks uh
more heavy duty truck traffic for those.
So, we just recommend those staying LI
and then we would recommend that the
southern third that is zoned LU in the
county be zoned to agricultural uh
agricultural in the city. Right now it
is just a residence. It is surrounded by
the AG zone in the city. Um and it would
just allow that property to continue as
is until they decided if they wanted to
redevelop it or do anything else with
it, they could reszone it.
So looking at those various um parcels
and staff's recommendations for them, uh
staff does believe those are the uh best
zones for each of the parcels and would
recommend approval of the assigned
zoning. I do want to just remind
everybody that we are talking about the
zoning. We're not talking anything about
the annexation. So, this is strictly on
does this zone is this zone that staff
is recommending appropriate for that
parcel
um based on
what the underlying zone is, the current
use, surrounding city zones
um and basically uses that could be
reasonably anticipated for those
properties.
And I stand for any questions. Uh
>> questions for staff from the commission.
Mr. Chair, of course, I've got a
question. Um,
did staff receive any feedback from any
of these owners expressing a preference
either for
uh the proposed zone designations or for
a different zone designation than what
is being proposed.
>> Yes. Uh, Mr. Mr. Chair, actually I would
say from two different property owners
and I can go through those. So Mr. Chair
through you to Commissioner Wigum. So in
what I've got on the screen for seven
what I counted as 7A. So it's the LI
portion. Um, I did receive a phone call
from one of the companies and they were
just kind of wondering what was going on
at first and um, would it change
anything for them and they would prefer
the LI zone as that is what they have in
the county and that is what currently
fits best for their property.
>> Otherwise, they have no issue with
everything else going on. Um, basically
they wanted they're fine with the LI
zone. And then the other one would be
the farm. uh they would like the AG zone
as that does allow the continuation of
that use.
>> Okay.
>> Okay then.
Thank you.
>> Any other questions for staff?
I guess the only thought I would have is
about the uh the complicated one there
on north of Fox Farm.
Uh,
and I know there's a there's a lot of
different things going on there. It's
surrounded by uh obviously a residential
type zoning now and it's in the future
land use mass land use map as
residential. So, but
I pro I probably agree with staff that
it's it's a tough one and the existing
use is LI. though it's probably easier
to leave it that way and see what needs
to happen with future development. Um
though I could see somebody arguing that
changing it to residential would sort of
uh be a little more forcing that type of
development in the future if that use
changed.
Any other questions?
>> Mr. Chair, through you. So we're we're
deciding on the zoning. When would the
annexation process when would that come
forth? Is that something
>> Mr. Chair through you? So the annexation
never comes before planning commission.
Uh the annexation goes before city
council and only city council and the
public hearing for that is next Monday
on the 9th.
So the zoning comes before um planning
commission as it's similar to a zone
change. So, it's one of those items
where
you give a recommendation. You kind of
review what zones staff is recommending
because if we do recommend something
that you don't believe is the correct
zone, you can recommend something else.
Uh, but with annexation and by state
statute, that just goes through council.
>> Mr. Chair, if I can clarify a little bit
of that as well.
This is Seth Lloyd with planning and
development. Mr. Chair, can I clarify
that as as well? Um, both the annexation
and the zone change are ordinances
through council. So, next Monday will be
the first reading. Um, generally the
council doesn't take action, although
the public hearing will allow for public
comment on the annexation. Um, then it
will go through committee and then
through council and assuming it passes
on second reading, it would go to third
reading. Um, so there's there's multiple
readings of both the zoning and the
annexation ordinance with final reading
happening. Um, I guess that would be
>> March 9th.
>> March 9th. Thank you, Connor. Um, just
just for enlightenment on the process.
Um, basically this commission is tasked
with what would the zoning be should the
council approve the annexation. So you
just you're running under the assumption
the annexation gets approved. If the
council decides not to approve the
annexation for any reason, the zone
would fail auto pretty much
automatically.
But chair for you to staff. Uh so I was
looking at some of the definitions that
we have and general agriculture and
limited agriculture are pretty vague.
Believe general agricultural the only
exclusion was swine feed lots that are
fed and maintained for 45 consecutive
days or more in a 12-month period. It's
a pretty broad swath. So I believe that
there's not many urban farms within the
city of Cheyenne and that is a big urban
planning concept. I was when I was at
school, we did a whole development north
of Salt Lake City and I was just curious
through this process if staff has had
any discussions at potentially revamping
our definition to be more inclusive of
that and considering
also the right to farm act and Wyoming
being an agricultural heavy state. Just
think that might be an area that our
definition is kind of
lackluster.
>> Mr. chair through you. Um, so staff
hasn't had discussions about those
specific definitions. Um, but and we'll
probably bring this up under other
business, we will have our annual review
discussion at our midmon planning
commission meeting this month. So maybe
that's something that planning
commission would like us to look into um
through that annual review process and
we can kind of look at that so we can
have more discussion at that midmon
meeting on that item.
Any other questions for staff?
Okay, we're going to open this up for
public comment. And just a reminder to
start, as Connor's mentioned several
times, this is this item for the
planning commission is strictly on the
zoning, the potential zoning for this
these likely to be annexed areas. But we
don't need we don't need comments about
the annexation itself, just the zoning
of the areas.
go ahead and come up to the podium and
please give your name and address.
>> Thank you. First of all, thank you chair
um committee and and uh staff for being
here working through these because I
know there's a lot going on. Um I my
name is Chelsea McCort. Um I'm a
resident here of Cheyenne. I live at
2518 Bent Avenue. So right over here. Um
firstly, I do want to be clear that I am
speaking regarding strictly the zoning
aspects of this and I am not talking
about the annexation. Um, I know that
there is a lot of confusion and a lot of
perhaps heated feelings about it. And so
I again am strictly speaking about the
zoning. Um, and this piggybacks off the
uh the comment that I'm sorry I don't
know your correct title, but Olsen
mentioned here um about urban farming
and the wider spectrum of how a is
zoned. Um, so via the the UDC um the a
zoning is very um open-ended. It's very
vague intentionally so that a lot of
things can occur under that zoning. Um,
however, for things like urban farms and
for things that are producers that rely
on that zoning, an open-ended can leave
gaps open to codes later coming in that
may disrupt operational procedures of
businesses. Um there's basically a gap
uh between the open-endedness of the a
zoning and a more restrictive
clarification that things like urban
farms require. Um that being said, the a
zoning is also used uh as as a um
according quote from the UC as a holding
zone for areas that may be further
developed, reubdivided, and reclassified
for the long term. Um we live in
Wyoming. Uh there's a lot of agriculture
around us. the city but buffs up against
a lot of um rural experience whether
they actually have agriculture on their
land or not is is kind of up in the air.
Um but there are some and so as the city
moves to incorporate more of the county
land I feel like this problem will show
itself ever more that um designating
both land that is intended for a holding
okay to later be developed and uh
classifying things like urban farms or
uh lands that have specific specific
agricultural purposes is very confusing
that their their joint designations. And
so again, going back with with uh
Representative Olsen, is that I don't
know. Commissioner Olsson, thank you. Um
that that uh
that looking specifically at that a
designation and further clarifying or
subdividing that ad a designation is
something that I think really needs to
be done as the city continues to
develop. Um,
yeah, that that's basically just it that
that I see a lot of concern about the
future as more agriculturally specific
groups get brought into the city.
>> So, I would uh sounds like you don't
necessarily have a specific comment on
one of these parcels and what we're
proposing. Of course, we're we're
working under the existing UDC such as
it is today and the definition such as
they are today. But if you if you do
have a suggestion as Commissioner Olsen
may have about uh changing those
definitions in the future or perhaps
uh maybe clarifying the way we handle
holding zones. Uh that might this this
is a good time to I don't know maybe
staff can tell us it's it's good to come
to our meeting in two weeks again or
bring or submit a comment or or
certainly through the uh governing body
because they're going to be considering
those same sorts of things. But uh is it
timely because this is the sort of the
annual time of year when people look at
the UDC and say what what things need to
be uh changed or strengthened.
>> I appreciate that. Uh chair could you
please clarify the the day and time if
you know it for when that upcoming
meeting is
>> chair through you. So that will the
annual review discussion will be on
February 17th, which is a Tuesday at 6
PM right here in council chambers.
>> Thank you. And I yield my time. Thank
you very much.
>> Uh just yes just any any other
commissioners have questions for this
person?
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> State your name and address, please.
David Nicely, 200 Waltershide. Um I
received notice of this process um
Tuesday of last week. Um so I didn't
receive what would be considered the
statutory expectation of notice because
the post's office didn't deliver
certified mail uh to an address that
they deliver mail to would and have been
notified as a correct address. Um, for
what it's worth, the legal address for
since the 1950s
um was not the mailing address. It's the
back of the property was the mailing
address because the post office didn't
want to deliver to the legal address,
but they've been notified to deliver the
mail that's addressed to the legal
address to the postal address and they
simply wrote on the certified mail that
um was expected to be delivered that
there's no such number.
So, I've had a week of whirlwind
and have been dumped out in a place that
I don't know that I'm in Wyoming anymore
and have asked repeatedly
for a chance to prepare.
Um, during that time, I've uh poured
messages over the wall to the city to
little answer. Um, and this is
addressing specifically the question,
did the um, property owners have an
opinion about the zoning?
And
Mr. Bloom has been very helpful in this
and we I appreciate him and and Connor.
Um, and I forget your last name, Connor,
but um, or I would have been more
respectful and used your last name, but
um,
I don't know what my opinion is.
I've had less than a week. I have not
been able to find
legal advice to advise me. I stand
before you not knowing what I should do
or even what I should say.
The planning department position is that
they are only required by the state
statute to mail a notice. They don't
have to be concerned about whether I
receive it.
I think that's a distinction
that's contrary to the spirit of the law
and maybe contrary to the law itself
because it's contrary to the spirit.
So I stand here to appeal to you
because there is no hurry. We've been
there for 19 years.
We bought it in the first place because
it was under development four times to
developers and the city would not permit
them to develop it. We have been farming
throughout.
Um we want to be left alone. We have no
problem with the county.
Um, the city has been a bad neighbor for
15 years. I'm sure we can continue that
relationship. I spoke to the mayor an
hour ago. It
have what's might be the start of
responsive improving relationship.
So, I'm asking you to simply
not make a decision tonight.
The city is working on answers to
questions we've asked, such as, "How can
we protect our livestock?
Historically, we've protected them with
firearms, but will not be permitted to
do that. Mountain lions have been half a
mile away. I've shot multiple coyotes.
There's foxes and roving packs of dogs.
So, there's no urgency.
>> Okay.
>> We didn't receive notice. Please
postpone."
>> Okay. You're you're kind of getting into
the annexation question a little bit
because the zoning doesn't have anything
to do with whether you can use firearms
or not.
>> I'm addressing the request for a
postponement. There is no urgency.
>> So your recommendation to the commission
is that we postpone this item. Uh
>> well, I'm not in a position to
recommend. I'm asking you. we that would
be fine with us. But
>> I would like to I would like to pursue
the question
potentially with legal advice of how I
should respond
to the planning commission and the
planning department asking you all to
zone us. I don't know. Even the
conversation I had an hour ago with the
mayor
indicated that maybe AG isn't the best,
but I don't know.
So again, we didn't receive notice.
Um
it may not even be within the bounds of
the law to make a determination.
Um but but I don't know. I'd like to
pursue
um legal advice.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Could you hold on for a second? We'll
see if any other commissioners have uh
questions for this commenter.
>> Will this new zoning that is being
proposed affect you? I mean, isn't it
the same zone as what you basically got
under the county?
>> I don't know.
I haven't had a chance to determine
that.
The county reszoned without asking me.
Um I continue to do what we do because
the state has a right to farm law and no
one can tell us to stop. From my
perspective,
it didn't matter.
>> So I don't know. Maybe I'm wrong in
that. I don't know.
I didn't receive notice until Tuesday
and I haven't had even a chance to have
extended conversations with city
planning. Um, as of Friday, Mr. Bloom
was still pursuing answers to questions
that we asked four years ago. Um, the
mayor doesn't know.
I don't know. Um, I don't know what you
do when I didn't receive notice and
don't know.
Um maybe you don't know and we all don't
know. Um I think there's a lot of don't
know and so if we want to make decisions
affecting the future of the city based
upon I don't know and you don't know and
they don't know well maybe that's the
way we plan.
>> Well Mr. chairman through you. Um the
staff has gone through and attempted to
mesh the city zones with the county as
best they can. Um
I don't think it's going to hurt you to
get it changed.
You're going to be in the same basic
zone that you're in now that that the
county has.
Do you understand that?
>> I understand the words you're saying.
I'm not sure
I agree or disagree because I don't
know. I'd like to pursue advice as to
how I even respond to that. And you'll
see that I'm not represented.
Mr. Chair, I think uh we've
pursued this as much as we can. I don't
know. We're not in any kind of position
to make any decisions other than to make
a vote.
>> Well, we'll continue on with comments
and any other questions for this this
commenter.
>> Uh Mr. Chair, this is Boyd Wigum through
you. I know we've already had the
presentation by the
staff as as the
applicant.
It would there be a way to split
this this item up into
the the parcels that
have a pretty clear answer. at least
don't have an appeal to
try to find out more
and and and hold back this item
uh for maybe postpone it to the
to the March meeting so that maybe some
more answers can be given and so we know
whether whether the the requested zone
or the proposed zone is
is okay with the with the land owner. Uh
because this is kind of a unique
situation. I you I feel like we're
trying to force a square peg into a
round hole. Logically, yeah, in my mind,
agriculture would make should be the
correct zone, but I don't think our city
agriculture zone is really designed for
agriculture so much as it's designed to
cover grazing land,
you know, at the periphery until until
it becomes something else like we saw
earlier when we were reszoning
for the the senior cooperative, senior
citizen cooperative. I is that is that
doable or do we need to keep everything
together
is is my question uh to staff through
you Mr. chair. And secondly,
um the staff have a different opinion on
on the urgency, the timeline of of
taking this up
given all the other calendars.
Chair, members of the planning
commission, Charles Bloom, playing
development director. um you you all are
the recommending body and the next step
is for this to go forward to the
governing body to be married with the
ordinance for the annexation. Those are
all set to start on Monday the 9th. Um
at that moment if they wish to divide
this, split this, pull this one out or
delay the entirety of the annexation.
That's an action that they could do. um
it probably would be best to make a
recommendation to allow them to um
decide if they want to continue to move
forward with this in whole or in part.
Um there are some questions that are
still outstanding. I've been trying to
work on being the point person for Mr.
Nicely and his wife to make sure we can
get the answers he's looking for. Uh
there are some questions regarding like
storm water for example and Mr. nicely.
It's I believe that it's approximately
$22 a month is what that would work out
um to to be for your storm water fee
that would be be there. We've talked
about a potential need for licensing
under the city clerk's office. There's a
$75 uh mobile food cart license that be
required. We've checked with city county
health about what would need to occur
regarding licensing from city county
health and they've indicated they're
operating under cottage uh food or food
law so there wouldn't be changes uh
there um there's questions on taxes
those would be answered by the county
assessor and those are a small uh change
in the mill levy um there's also a
couple other questions that are are out
there regarding the use of uh firearms
which I was able to get an closer to
that uh just recently before the end of
the day today where the discharge of any
firearm in the city outside of a a
shooting range that's approved by the by
the city or the county is prohibited. So
the animal control uh via
discharge of a firearm would not be um
an allowed use and there talking with
Chief Francisco there would not be um an
issue with I mean there would not be the
ability to issue an exception for for
this. Um again there's also the
discussions of uh the right to farm act
which is one that's separate of zoning
and that's at the statutory level and
it's our understanding that the right to
farm act is one that um says you're able
to continue farming um and producing any
odors, sounds, noises, those types of of
items that are customary with farming.
Um, in the event, you know, that you
have neighbors that move in that wish to
challenge that, um, there are elements
that would, um, not be protected under
the Right to Farm Act, let's say, for
example, he decided to open up a welding
shop that was open for business on the
property, that's not a protected use of
the Right to Farm Act, or if there was a
junkyard that was to be established or
nuisances that were to be created. Both
of all of those cases would be items
that would not be lawful in the
unincorporated county under their
current uh nuisance um and zoning
practices or in the city. Um but what
we've done is a lot of the information
that we've put together, these are all
items that are independent of the
zoning. U when we did identify that the
a zoning was best for the city um and
for the owner. Um, what that really did
is that removed the fear that the farm
stand and the farm use would be a
non-conforming use and subject to
additional review when it when it moves
forward. But we are going to continue to
get the answer to these questions and um
we'll continue to communicate with Mr.
Nicely to make sure he can have this
information.
>> Okay.
I guess as a followup, I'd like to ask a
follow-up question. Um,
through you to staff, is it impossible
to uh to postpone this to the next
I guess the March meeting
uh in order to allow Mr. nicely to
determine whether he objects to the A
zoning or has a different preferred
zoning as he understands what he's
trying to do and and the constraints. I
I don't intend to slow down any of the
other processes here. I don't want to
get beyond that, but I do think that if
we're going to
do an assigned zoning as opposed to
requested zoning,
I would feel more comfortable
thinking that we've done our job by
allowing somebody who has their doubts
about what we're doing uh to at least
voice a voice a preference
or at least voice a preference within a
reasonable time. You know, obviously we
can't wait for five years for the
preference, but
or is that bow everything up down
downstream?
>> Chair threw you to um Mr. Wigum. Um the
you're welcome to to request a postpone
on any action in front of you and that
would be up for a vote of the planning
commission if they want to postpone and
continue action on this public hearing.
Um, regarding the zoning assignment, uh,
we've gone through multiple county
pockets and we did have a little change
in the way county, uh, or establishment
of zoning changed throughout time with
the county's land or zoning map change.
But the standard for all developers,
including the one you saw here earlier
today, is staff suggest an assigned
zoning that meets the criteria under
unified development code. And if the
landowner seeks anything different,
whether it be for a 54 unit multifamily
structure, they are able to proceed with
that amendment on their own, paying the
notification cost and application fees
for that item. With the recent section
20 annexation, uh that is just wrapping
up, which is where that multif family
development is. We did have requests
from other land owners to seek other
zoning that was more intense than what
we identified as acceptable um assigned
zoning through the annexation. So I just
wanted to note that if you all do
postpone
um
it wouldn't be to uh consider a
different zoning than what staff is
recommending for establishment. Um it
would essentially be the ability for the
landowner to say I don't like that
zoning um or I do like that zoning and
for them to inform the planning
commission that they would proceed with
a zoning amendment separately and
independent of this process which would
follow it up after it's complete.
>> Thank you Mr. Chair. So ju just to
clarify for my benefit, I think
Commissioner Wiggins original question
was, is it possible for us, I don't know
how the rest of the comments going to go
in the rest of the discussion, but is it
possible if ultimately the commission is
comfortable with six out of seven of
these parcels with the recommended
zoning to make a motion that recommends
approval of those six but recommends but
postpones or recommends denial of the
seventh? Is that is that mixed motion
possible?
Chair three of the planning commission.
It would become increasingly problematic
uh because it would change the structure
of the application that we're
processing. Um,
it is possible, but it would lead to a
lot of
we have to have all of our paperwork in
by Wednesday at noon. So, we would be
spending the next 12 hours with our
attorney's office directing all of our
resources to reddrafting that and
determining whether or not uh there are
other implications that we're not aware
of.
you could make a recommendation
um to move it forward noting that
you you all do not believe that zoning
is appropriate for the parcel that's
being discussed. However, that
would again result in a lot of
confusion in the process.
Mr. Chair, through you. I just have a
comment. I feel like I don't think I
could actually approve this with knowing
that one of the property owners is
doesn't understand. He still wants to do
some due diligence on this. And
unfortunately, I don't understand why we
had seven parcels on one item where what
if we didn't like, you know, we didn't
agree with one, we didn't agree with
three. I mean, that would just seems
like a lot of confusion. Anyways, to the
point where this is something that
should have been considered as far as
what if you know we're not going to
always agree on every single item like
we are right now. We're not agreeing.
Well, I'm not cuz I still want parcel 4
to be excluded from cuz I mean on the
other six I don't mind, but I'm going to
have a I'm probably going to vote no if
we have to deal on all of them.
Mr. Chair through you you just boy this
is big boy wig again. So as I understand
it we've got two choices. We can either
advance this recommendation to the city
council or we can postpone it for
consideration, further consideration to
determine whether or not we agree that
that uh the recommended assigned zones
are the most appropriate zone under the
stat under the ordinance that we have
for assigned zonings.
Um, I guess my comment is it was a
really good process until the county
decided to get squirly with their zoning
code and then it now there's more
I guess more gray area and I think we're
running into that. Um, the a zoning
seems to make sense to me as being an
assigned zone, but it it sounds to me
like
it may it still may not necessarily
permit
the existing uses to the extent that the
landowner
would per and I don't know maybe the
landowner has to has to choose which
uses are the most important to continue
as conforming uses.
Um,
but it sounds to me like our choices are
either to advance the entire thing or
postpone the entire thing for a month to
get more information, more clarity
around what the appropriate designated
assigned zones are. not necessarily a
zoning map amendment, but to make sure
that what we're proposing as the
assigned zoning is
is the correct assigned zoning. If
there's question about whether or not
the recommendation is is correct,
>> Mr. Chair, if I may as well because
we're bringing up what the original
county zone was. The original county
zone for this property before the LU was
MR, medium density residential.
If we had our old assigned zoning
when that was still happening, the uses
would be non-conforming and would not be
permitted in the MR zone.
So, with the new assigned zoning,
we actually would allow it with the AG
zone.
So, I just wanted to make that
clarification because I know we're
starting to get into, well, what was it
prior to or under the old assigned
zoning and old county zone? The old
county zone was medium density
residential, which would have been
assigned city medium density
residential, which would not have
permitted the current uses and would
have made them non-conforming.
Okay, just to make sure I'm on track
with where we're at in the process. We
we had comments from Mr. Nicely. Mr.
Nicely still at the podium and I had
been asking if there are questions for
Mr. Nicely and then we got into some
clarifications from staff on some
questions and a little bit of commentary
about what we might uh construct as a
motion ultimately on this item. But
let's get back to the questions from Mr.
Nicely. Are there any more of those from
the commissioners? Uh, Mr. Chair, and I
I'll get back on track. Uh, through you
to Mr. nicely.
Given the conversation that we've had,
um, do you still object to advancing
using the AG zone or would it be
acceptable to
apply to you to apply for a reasonzoning
if you find out that the AG zoning is
not
is less protective of what you need to
protect than
another alternative?
Uh third alternative uh given that you
an attorney who specializes and sits on
the planning commission just said a few
minutes ago that you don't know. Um I
still don't know and if you don't know I
don't know. I need time to think about
it and wasn't given notice to think
about it. Um, so
I would like to have opportunity to
determine whether or not I accept the AG
designation or I want to choose to apply
for a different designation. I feel a
bit like a bride who was kidnapped,
taken before the judge and asked to
affirm that she will marry the suitor.
I don't like the position that I've been
put in. I would have preferred that
someone had come to us and said we which
is courteous and respectful and kind. We
would like to annex you.
Does this work for you? And how can we
make this work for you? I had an
extended discussion with the mayor
finally after five days of asking for
one.
that we committed to begin talking about
such things. We are not cookie cutter
zoning.
We are not a cookie cutter thing. The
mayor himself said, "I don't know. I
don't think about farms. I don't know
anything about farms."
So,
okay. Well, you think about farms and
I'll think about farms in the city and
we'll come to an agreement to a
discussion. Mr. Olsen's
proposal that we consider
ordinances for urban farming
makes sense.
I my background is in philosophy and
theology and I work on the railroad and
I farm.
You know, in philosophy and theology,
500 years isn't that long. And in
Europe, farms exist for 500 years in the
same family.
I've asked continuously for planning to
give me a 40-year plan for what they
expect to do as a city. And I'll give a
40-year plan of what we expect to do as
a farm.
And we'll make gentleman's agreements
and we'll trust each other and we'll
help each other and we'll do it. And all
I get is adversarial
activity after adversarial activity. I
asked nicely
last Wednesday for a postponement
and what I'm told is mere form
mere formal compliance with the law
without
fulfilling the spirit of the law is
acceptable.
Um
I don't I don't think I'm in Wyoming
anymore.
Um, I don't know where the wizard is,
but
I don't feel like I'm in Wyoming
anymore. So, the answer is not. Neither
of Mr. Wigum is neither of your
proposals. A third, I get some time to
think about it.
Uh, more questions, other questions for
the up or the commenter.
Okay, Mr. Chairman, one quick question.
I'm sorry, but for for uh uh the staff
is
was he non-conforming under the original
county zoning if it was medium
residential and two members of the board
through you to uh Commissioner Mia
correct, he was not conforming under the
county regulations.
Okay. Uh, we'll continue with
>> this just I'm sorry, but this just seems
like
we've moved him into a conforming zone
from a non-conforming zone. The m the
the uh county must have done that when
they redid their zoning system and we're
trying to keep him in a a conforming
zone. I guess I I fail to understand
what the problem is with with Mr.
Nestle. I know he didn't get his notice
until uh a week ago. That's not our
fault. We do the best we can. Anyway,
that's all I have to say.
Mr. Nicely,
>> I I I presume what you I presume your
position is that you're that this is a
complex question. what this what uses
exactly are allowed under that zoning or
the other possible zonings and and it's
you're you're trying to clarify those
questions in your mind and decide what
uh would be best. And so it's it's not a
simple matter of saying you're you you
were non-conforming and now you're going
to be conforming in this city zone uh
because you may well not be. For
example, the firearms thing is a is
something that you would no longer be
allowed, which you are now.
>> Well, yes. I mean, and that firearms
thing threatens our existence as a farm
with livestock because we will not and
cannot have livestock if we cannot
protect it.
Um, so, um, we may have a right to farm
law, but if the city has an ordinance
that does not allow us to pursue a farm
and no answer to how we can protect
livestock and has systematically and the
party the city has systematically
through drainage destroyed our fences,
then
we are
again the city might be within formal
compliance to some understanding of the
law that we're allowed to farm though
they've structurally
evicted us from farming on our farm. Um,
again,
I don't know if Mr. Wigum doesn't know I
and I've known Boyd for a few years now.
He's he's
a sharp attorney. If he sits here and
doesn't know, then
given five, six days
to think about it, I don't know.
Um I again I I was hopeful that this
would just go away through some fairy
tale thought that Wyoming was too
committed to liberty to forcefully annex
anyone. And I was told by Mayor Spiker
years ago that the city never forcefully
annexes anyone. So I had expectations
um when we set out that that would never
happen. Um so my word to the city is
pick a lane and stay in it. You you've
come out of your lane. Um and now with
six days you want me to adjust and
express an opinion about your driving.
Um,
so the most charitable, kind, and
respectful thing I can say is
I'd like to think about it
and I'd like
to pursue advice as to the lawfulness of
it. I'm not convinced that the notice
requirement was lawfully fulfilled
and that this meeting is even legal.
So,
I could ask you to rule for yourself
whether or not this meeting is legal.
Um, and maybe that's the right thing to
do if an attorney were standing beside
me, but I haven't been given that
opportunity.
But
I didn't get notice.
Okay. I I I I think we I think we were
kind of repeating and I and I know I
think we understand that that that part
of the uh your assertion
um and and your concern and the fact
that you still don't
uh haven't had time to, you know, come
up with what you what you really want to
do. I I I think we understand that. I
don't think uh I mean I I think we
>> So are you comfortable
um
moving forward in the face of my my
request to pursue legal advice in a
legal hearing?
>> Well, I can't I can't speak for the
commission at this point.
>> Well, that was rhetorical.
>> Yeah. So, we're we'll continue on with
comment and discussion and eventually
we'll have a motion or more than one
motion and we'll we'll make our decision
and then the governing body um I I guess
the good news is the governing body will
make final actions and they they will
take several uh what at best best case
March 9th a final decision. So, you've
you've got a number of opportunities
between here and now besides tonight to
uh to to get that uh your points through
that way. So,
can we uh do we have more comment or
please ma'am?
>> Hey, thank you. I'm Tommy Nicely. I'm
live reside at 200 Wide Boulevard. I'm
the owner of Whiteresh Farms and um
Mr. Olton really
got down to it saying the A zoning is
just so vague and we have asked for some
clarification on how we can continue my
operation, how I can continue my
livelihood by being zoned in the city um
and trying to comply with the city and
county. Um Mr. Robert, I'm sorry, I
don't know how to pronounce your last
name, but we when we purchased the
property, it was zoned medium density
residential. Um, when I started my
farming in 2017, I contacted the county
and said, "This is what I want to do.
Can I do it? And how do I do it?" And
they they did not tell us to reszone.
They told me to apply for a at home
>> home home based business
>> at home homebased business which I did
to try to comply. We also went back to
the county to say what about like taxes
for a land or even get an egg and we
were told by the county that vegetables
were not crops. So, um I mean we are
trying
um and if you ask me who I all talk to,
I don't know. There's so much
government. I mean I'm just trying to
grow vegetables for Cheyenne um and give
them access to food security and fresh
food. And so um we have some legitimate
concerns again with the a zoning being
very um vague which we've expressed
those concerns to the city that um would
they work with us um you know could they
provide some assurances
and I don't know so far I
um we haven't gotten very far and um I
mean I'm sorry that this would cost the
city time and money and effort. Um,
but I think it's better that the city
absorbs it than forcing it on its
citizens who just are trying to keep
their livelihood. I mean, um, I I have
some concerns and willing to work on
maybe
making something really great for urban
farms. Is that something that Cheyenne
wishes to pursue?
Um
all
>> okay. Uh questions for Miss Nicely.
>> Okay. Hearing none. Are there add is
there additional public comment? Anyone
uh either in the room or online?
Public comment going once. Public
comment going twice. Public comment
closed.
So, uh, staff, do you have any further
clarifications before we ask for a
motion?
Chair three to the plan, members of the
planning commission, Charles Bloom,
planning, development director. I'm
presently just sending a quick message
to our city attorney just to get some
appropriate guidance right now because
it's under the understanding that right
now you have three options under this
assigned zoning action. Um, number one
is recommend the city council that the
application be approved. That's one
option. Number two is recommend to the
city council that the application be
approved with specific conditions or
modifications. So that's the second one.
And then third one is recommend to the
city council that the application be
denied stating the specific reasons for
denial.
Um so the
the um advice of the attorney is that it
is not appropriate for um a division of
the ordinance to occur. So what if you
could do is you could send forward a
recommendation um to approve with
modifications with a modification being
that this particular piece of land not
be included in the zoning or an
alternative zone be explored.
So that would move it forward to the
governing body where they could identify
if it would be appropriate to uh to uh
look at a different uh zoning. They
could also bring up a discussion on
notice. They could make that decision if
they felt notice was meant. I would like
to note that on December 16th, we did
have an open house, which we've had for
all of our county pocket mailings where
we do mail letters to all property
owners um that are in the county pockets
to attend. And that was held on December
16th where Mr. nicely and his wife did
attend and they were distributed a
handout which had the entire schedule of
every action regarding the zoning and
the annexation that was provided to them
in advance of the formal certified mail.
We always end that meeting by saying
here is the list of dates that are
coming. You will be receiving a
certified mail in the future. That will
be the official public hearing notice
that was returned to our office and
within 60 minutes of that landing in our
inbox. We did scan that and email it to
Mr. Nicely since we've been in contact
with him for just under four years on
this annexation action.
>> Any other questions for staff before I
ask for a motion?
Hearing
none, I will ask for a motion from the
commission.
Mr. Chair,
>> go ahead. Commissioner,
>> would you accept? Would you be willing
to accept a little bit of reflection to
help frame a motion at this point or do
you want to just do that process through
amendments to a main motion? I I think
it would be efficient to have the
reflection first.
So go ahead if you have comments that
might help frame a motion.
What I am hearing
is
I think well first we need to be really
careful here.
It's not our purview
whether property is annexed or not.
And I I think we've covered that ground
fairly well. And and it's my
understanding that whatever
recommendation we make is only applied
if the parcels
involved here, if any all of the parcels
involved here
are finally annexed into the city. and
and it kind of from what I much of the
discussion I heard was that a lot of the
objection is to the annexation in the
first place. Now obviously the second qu
the following question is if if annexed
what do we do you know in terms of a
zoning or a lack of zoning? Um, we've
kind of That was the mess that got us to
where we have these assigned zonings.
I don't love assigned zoning either. Uh,
they're just there's a lot about this
process that I don't like it. it.
However you slice it, it seems
potentially heavy-handed, but
and and I think we kind of know that my
strong preference is is the user of land
should
their preference should weigh heavily in
what we do.
I think we probably the best answer I
think would be to propose
to make a recommendation to the city
council and if and if there's an
alternative to the a zoning that that
would be more in line with what our the
code that we have to follow says is is
appropriate for our assigned zoning.
Then we make that recommen make that
change and and recommend what we think
is is most appropriate under the UDC.
Um
I'm not afraid to postpone this. It may
foul up the city, but I'm not afraid to
postpone this. But I'm afraid that we'll
get into the weeds cuz really all
all we have is are we making a
recommendation of zonings for all these
various parcels each of which we believe
is the most appropriate zoning
generally given historical use existing
use. You know what? Again, which round
hole does the square peg fit best into?
Um, my instinct is probably the egg
zoning is is
going to come out being the best, but
the only thing I think if we postpone
this, the only thing we would be
postponing it for would be for an
objection to one of the proposed
assigned zonings as being not the most
appropriate one.
given the constraints of our code.
Um,
I'm still torn. I'm still torn
um to either
propose advancing it as is because I do
think that as a s I was glad to see that
it was an a zoning or postponement. But
I would not have any appetite for more
than one postponement. And it sounds to
me like this is there have been ongoing
conversations as distasteful as they may
have been.
So, I've got a problem with with the
formal legal notice because I rely on
those in my day job and there's things
that I know come are coming down the
pike, but until I receive notice,
they're not really there. They're just
the idea of being there. So,
with that,
I'm curious what the rest of the
commission thinks on on how to approach
this. And I'm thankful that this may be
the last forced forced annexation we
have to do in assigned zoning.
Uh, Director Bloom, just to clarify
again, you you were conveying something
you'd heard from the city attorney
recently that
the the one option we might have would
be to recommend approval of the assigned
zoning, but with a commentary that there
was some concern about this one parcel.
Is that the gist of it? What would that
motion look like or sound like?
And chair, members of the planning
commission, uh, for clarification, just
I'm going to say two two things real
quick. Number one, all three of your
actions that you're able to take under
under our unified development code all
involve recommendations. Recommendation
to approve, recommendation to deny or
recommendation that the application be
approved with specific conditions or
modifications. So, there is not an
option to postpone. Um in discussion
with the city attorney uh he had
indicated that uh there are fundamental
issues with a division of this item
because it creates uh problems with the
application and it creates problems with
the other ordinances that are dependent
on this component. Um there could be the
option for a recommendation to the city
council
that this particular parcel be explored
for alternative zoning where that
question would then be uh sent to the
governing body. They call it city
council and code. Governing body, city
council, they go back and forth. Um and
then they can make a decision to zone it
to something alternative. They could
make the decision to just delete this
property completely from the zoning
amendment and make the corresponding
change to the annexation action, but
they have the ability to keep those two
projects aligned.
So, an appropriate motion if you're
looking for one that has a
recommendation that addresses Mr. and um
Mrs. Nicely's
uh concerns would be something to move
to recommend
the city council approve
this zoning application subject to
uh requested modification that the
zoning for Mr. and Mrs. nicely as
property be evaluated for alternative
zoning
proposals
and that would allow it to move forward
and then that would move the discussion
forward to the governing body where they
can make that decision.
Mr. Chair, I think where I can kind of
help if that's the direction we're
leaning on going of where to place it.
you'd basically have the entirety of
this first motion down to as shown in
the attached zone change map and then
basically comma
um with the modification that parcel 4
or I would if you say parcel 4 I know
how what that means um and I can make
that work uh parcel 4
basically be explored for alternative
zoning and then noting that the
application meets the review criter for
approval.
Something along those lines is where I
would put it in the motion. Um, so that
you are still recommending approval of
all the other zones for all the other
parcels with that modification that
specifically parcel 4 be explored for
alternative zoning.
>> Mr. Chair, Boyd Wigum through you. Um, I
would like to note that that we've got
an assigned zoning. So the when we're
talking about alternative zoning, this
isn't selected zoning. I think the only
question is is there a different zoning
district that is a more appropriate
assigned zoning. So I think using
referring to assigned zoning,
alternative assigned zoning
>> would be appropriate if if we're going
to go down that road.
>> I don't understand why we can't
postpone. That doesn't make sense to me.
and but
because we can basically postpone till
we're convinced that something's ready
for prime time at least historically.
But if we are going to make a
recommendation advance this, I think we
need to specify that that we're within
the code and that that we just have our
doubts that that the proposed the
suggested assigned zoning on this parcel
may not be
the the most appropriate under code.
So, I would I would emphasize assigned
zoning, alternative assigned zoning.
>> Any other thoughts about uh what you'd
like to see for a motion or what we
could see for a motion from the
commission?
Okay. So, I'll ask again if someone if
one of the commissioners would like to
make a motion.
Mr. chair Boyd Wiggum.
I am going to want to have a little bit
of help because I'm going to borrow from
from
Mr. White's
uh recommended word smithing
generally. Okay. I move to recommend the
governing body approve the assigned zone
zoning for land, pardon me, east of I25,
south of the intersection of Westland
Road and Missile Drive, north of West
of West and East Allison Road and east
of and adjacent to North College Drive
to AG Agricultural, MR Medium Density
Residential, CB Community Business, and
LI light industrial is shown on the
attached zone change map. Uh
with the caveat that I re that we
recommend that uh parcel number four on
the change map be re-evaluated for alter
uh more appropriate alternative assigned
zoning
prior to final action. Noting that the
project meets the review criteria for
approval.
>> Second.
>> Mr. Chair,
>> go ahead. Commissioner Wig,
>> is there any explanation why
postponement is not an alternative?
And I'm afraid that advice from city
from city attorney got into the weeds on
division. That was kind of a passing
thought. It was pretty clear that that
wasn't going to work. But why is
postponement not an option?
D
chair three to commissioner Wigum. In in
the Unified Development Code, we're very
prescriptive on what the actions are for
hearings. Um for the hearings we have
for uh subdivisions and and other items,
there's a clear um option for the
planning commission to postpone um
essentially it says postpone to resolve
um other issues that were identified
during the meeting or to postpone to
seek additional information. With the
assigned zoning, it is set up in a way
that it is either a recommend yes,
recommend no, or recommend a
modification. It doesn't have that
option for postponement.
>> Mr. Chair, m Mr. Chair,
>> just found Mr. Chair, I think we just
found another item to add to the list of
annual review criteria then if we don't
have postponement because
>> not not that it's going to issue be an
issue going forward, but
>> Mr. Chair, this is Seth's planning
development department. Admittedly, the
assigned zoning was originally written
with the purpose of addressing uh
applicant submitted annexations and the
way state statute works with annexations
and lining up ordinances. We have to
certify mail long before time to get uh
annexation on the council agenda, which
is what's the way state statute is. So
in order to keep projects moving for our
applicants, um the assigned zone is
written so that the zoning can be heard
at the same time the annexation is being
heard. We can't postpone the public
hearing because that was noticed in
newspapers and by certified mailing to
all the property owners. Obviously the
post office messed up one. Um but
everyone who's anticipating that public
hearing already it's already going to
happen on next Monday. And so the
rationale behind the assigned zoning not
having a postponement option is because
a the assigned zoning is supposed to be
a pretty straightforward process. It's
it's the base zone. It's the most basic
zone that we can assign a parcel. B we
already have the assign the annexation
going to council. Now once again the
assigned zoning was kind of written with
an applicant submitted annexation in
mind, not necessarily the city initiated
annexations in mind. This is also the
last city initiated annexation. So, um,
we could possibly look into changing
that process a little bit, but the
challenge here is that the annexation
and the zone change, um, it's definitely
not best practice to have an annexation
without um, zoning the land to give
owners clarity as to what they can do.
And so, postponing the zoning now, does
the governing body have to postpone the
annexation to line them up again? It it
gets confusing in that direction. And if
we have concerns like we do today, the
governing body can always postpone both
items together. They can postpone the
annexation. They can postpone the zoning
until we get the right land on the right
zone. So that's the rationale behind the
assigned zoning not having a
postponement option. All of our other
applications don't have that problem. Um
it's only the assigned zoning because
it's tied to an annexation. It's
basically the second half of annexation
and the annexation is already going. Um,
and so we have the the assigned zoning
trying to keep up with the annexation.
>> Okay, we have a motion and a second.
More discussion.
>> I'd like to hear the motion again.
>> So So maybe I don't Robert, can you read
what's on the screen? I think it's
exactly that except before the last
comma, Boyd inserted the language with
the caveat that we recommend that parcel
4 be evaluated for more appropriate
assigned zoning.
Is that what you had, Connor?
>> I'm glad you had the language before
final adoption in there.
>> For final adoption, I was trying to
write it down as he was saying. that
review would occur before the final
reading and vote is our recommendation
or at least what I thought.
>> Would that stop the whole thing from
going
>> Mr. Chair through you? No, that would
not stop. Basically, staff would have to
look at the uses, which I would like to
just clarify on the uses really quick as
well. When it comes to our agricultural
uses, there are two zone districts.
There's the AG and then very very
limited agriculture is allowed in the
AR.
So almost all agricultural uses are
allowed in the AG. Um there is some
caveats. I think one or two of them is a
conditional use but general agricultural
limited agricultural are permitted in
the AG. Limited agricultural is
permitted in the AR but general agricult
general agricultural is not. So any
agricultural use those are the only two
zone districts. Otherwise we start
looking at the airport zone district or
our is it support services zone district
which was not meant for anything other
than military
um basically over um by the military
base was for the SS. So the only two
city zones we most likely can even look
at for an agricultural style use is AG
or AR
and based on the use the AG does give
the most flexibility.
So we will have to evaluate these two
with the uses and provide that to
council with an additional evaluation
but it would not stop the process. It
would just we basically have till I
would say public service committee on
February 17th
uh to basically evaluate and provide
that information with uh the committee
at that point.
>> Yeah. My concern was the last three
words that Mr. Boyd used which was
before final adoption. Would that stop
the whole process?
That's my question.
>> Mr. Chair thun. I don't believe so
because the final adoption would be
March 9th. So we would just have to
evaluate and provide the evaluation to
council for their consideration and that
they're the ones who ultimately will
decide.
So it it would not stop the process.
>> Mr. Chair, through you to Commissioner
Ma. The notion here is I'm not certain
uh a re-evaluation would do much good if
it happened if it was delivered in April
or May or June. And so as near as I can
tell,
um our landowner
wants an opportunity to weigh in on on
what he thinks is the most appropriate
assigned zoning. And I think we're I
think this is as good a cav as good a
carve out as we can provide
under the code as it's been presented to
us
while allowing this to proceed and marry
up with the with the annexation
ordinance.
Any uh further discussion?
Staff, could you call the role, please?
Lonnie Olsen.
>> Hi.
>> Bob Mati.
>> No,
>> Daryl Hibbons.
>> Hi.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> Id Wiggum.
>> I.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
Staff, could you read item D into the
record?
>> Item D, PUDC-26-4
Bison Business Park fifth filing zoning
map amendment.
>> Mr. Evans is still here.
>> Yeah. Chairman, planning commission
members, Brad Evans, AVI, uh, agent for
the owner, Lumus Livestock Company.
Before you is a zone change from, uh,
agricultural to BP. Um, this is a parcel
of land. It's kind of interesting. We
just talked a lot about holding zones of
AG. This was zoned AG as a holding zone
originally. Uh, they do have, uh,
somebody interested in this parcel now,
so we're reszoning it to BP. Um, if you
notice in some of the maps, the county
map servers haven't been updated yet.
So, this is an expansion of the BP zone.
It's not a BP by itself. It's an
expansion of the two lots to the east.
Um, and I'll be happy to answer any
questions that the commission has for
this
>> commissioners. Questions for the
applicant?
>> Through you, Mr. Chair. Um, I have a
question. when I look at the map and I
went out to the property today, kind of
took a peek at it, so I understood cuz
the drawing that I have on the map isn't
consistent with what it where it says it
is. It says it's located west of South
Gley Avenue when in fact it's located
east of South Gley. So, I just wanted to
confirm. I don't know if that's cities
doing their diagram wrong or or what,
but I noticed that right away. It's on
opposite sides of dot. So, I don't know
if it means anything, but it kind of
threw me off a little bit. I thought I'm
on the wrong side of the road, but I
wasn't.
>> This parcel is definitely east of South
Korea Highway.
>> More questions for the applicant?
Um um Mr. Chair, through you uh was
there any feedback from the homeowners
on the opposite side of the highway to
this? Were did any comments come in that
we should be aware of or maybe come in
before after the deadline?
>> Mr. Chairman, through AVI, we have not
received any calls or comments for this
project.
>> Mr. chair throughu what are the plans
what are you guys planning on building
out there
>> um Mr. chairman through you. I believe
it's uh for a company the company that
we talked to was for uh support the data
centers. Um so but I don't know if
that's a finalized any of that. That's
just what um got the process started to
get this moving from AG to BP.
Any other questions for the applicant?
>> Okay staff, you have a report. Chair and
members of the commission counterway
planning and development department. So
this project is located south of Dea
Lane and west of South Gley Highway. I
guess I should be east. Yeah, I had that
wrong.
My apologies. Um this parcel is within
um Bison Business Park. So this is down
in an actual business park. Um, as the
applicant mentioned on the zoning side
where it says HI maps haven't been
updated, that has been reszoned to BP.
So that did come before you. It did have
the recommendation of approval and did
get reszoned by city council to BP
zoning. So this parcel is not trying to
basically get BP zoning on its own. Um,
even I believe the AG parcel to the
south of that HI has been reszoned to
BP. So they do meet the uh requirement
to have 320 acres to be allowed the BP
zone. Future land use map does designate
this area as industrial. So that BP zone
does fit with the future land use map.
Again surrounding zoning there is the
residential that is in the county to the
west and then you do have the BP zone uh
that is within uh the Bison business
park already. So BP does exist and this
would be a continuation of that zoning.
Uh the BP zone allows for more of a cond
mixed commercial industrial um type
development. Uh so it allows some of our
commercial uses along with industrial
uses in that zone district.
Um
as Mr. Edmmonds had mentioned with the
AG zone being the holding zone. Uh that
was also at the time of platting. They
zoned it a AG so they wouldn't have to
pay the community facility fees at the
time of platting. Again, this commission
did make a text amendment where now
those fees are due at time of building
permit. So even with this resoning,
there won't be any of those fees due
until basically a building permit um is
applied for.
With that, staff does recommend approval
of this BP zone. And I'm available for
any questions.
Uh, questions for the staff from the
commission.
Hearing none, I'll open this up for
public comment. Anyone from the public,
either in the room or online, would like
to comment on this item for or against.
Public comment going once. going twice,
going three times, and public comment is
closed.
Any uh clarification now that you've
heard comments, Mr. Emmens?
Okay.
So, the chair would entertain a motion
from the commission.
>> Uh chair, I move to approve the resoning
of Bison Business Park, fifth filing to
BP Business Park as shown in the
attached zone change map. Noting that
the project meets the review criteria
for approval.
>> Second.
Any discussion on the item?
>> Staff, please call the role.
>> Wiggle. I.
>> Amy Hernandez.
>> I
Mathia,
>> yes.
>> Lonnie Olson,
>> I
>> and Daryl Hibbons.
>> Yes.
>> Mr. Chair, that motion passes.
>> Okay, that moves us on to item five in
the agenda, other business and staff
announcements.
>> Chair, mayors of planning commission,
Charles W, planning and development
director. Just wanted to note that the
urban renewal authority board will be
meeting on Thursday the 5th of this
month at 10 a.m. in this room. They'll
be considering a revised blight study
that will essentially look at the
entirety of the community and do a
communitywide declaration of blight. Uh
what it what it will do is it will
essentially look at the relevant pieces
of the uh previous plans and studies
that have been done and it has
evaluations of about five new areas of
the community as well including East
Lincoln Way, South Cheyenne, Swan Ranch,
the Dell Range District, and the
Yellowstone District up north. Uh that
plan is a is available online at
www.chyanscity.org.
org/ur
for urban indu authority. It's right
there smack dab on the middle of the
page. It is a 100page document with
about uh 75 pages of that document being
uh blight surveys and also photographic
evidence. So the real meat of is about
24 pages. Um that's done in a rush to
move forward to the governing body. So
um it will take probably a few weeks to
be introduced to the governing body as
we move forward with um that resolution
being drafted. One thing I would like to
know is as part of this discussion we
sought the ability to create a blight
study that would essentially evolve and
grow on its own essentially um as city
limits expanded. What what happens is
when you declare an area blight, you've
created an area of operation, which
means this is where you can do urban
renewal um activities. Um it's been uh
determined after looking at in numerous
ways that we can't make it automatically
grow on its own. It will have to be
amended in the future um as it as a city
um grows. Um as a reminder, blight
studies do not go to the planning
commission on purpose. they did once on
accident
and they um do go directly to the
governing body. Um and a blight study
just opens the door for urban renewal
plans and projects which you will do
review and make recommendations on.
Um we do have a midmon meeting that will
be our annual review. We will have a
quick 101 training session. Uh that will
be on the 17th of February, 6 o'clock
p.m. here. Um if we will have a memo
that will be put out approximately a
week prior and we did have a work
session with the governing body on the
23rd uh which was the 14th birthday for
the adoption of unified development code
that was adopted on the 23rd in 20
uh 20 12. Yes, in 2012. Um, that one was
a little bit abbreviated because they
got hung up on multifamily housing. So,
they kind of started here a lot of
discussion and then it became a
whirlwind towards the end. So, feel free
to catch that on the YouTube channel or
Facebook if you want a little bit of a
preview prior to getting the staff
report.
So, those are all the updates I have.
Seth, Connor, Morgan, Aaron.
All right. No updates.
>> Well, real quick, Mr. Sure. Um, underway
planning and development. I believe I
should have sent out an email with the
new UDC that had the campground
regulations in it finally. Um, so that's
in there. The
text amendment for ADUs will be on third
and final reading next Monday. So that
means I get to update the UDC again. So
say probably in a couple weeks, expect
another email with a new UDC. Any
other items, questions?
Remind me. Do I need to move to adjurnn
or do I just adjurnn? We are adjourned.